

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211









Engineer- Cloud & Infra Services seeking roles in Middleware Administration, Requirement Analysis, Application Design, Middleware

Development, Software Coding, Software Testing, TIBCO

EMS, Administrator, Hawk, JDBC, JMS, Perl Script, SQL, PL/SQL, Shell Script

Current Designation: Engineer- Cloud & Infra Services

Current Company: Larsen & Toubro Infotech

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore. Chennai. Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming

Role: Tech Support Enanr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Engineer- Cloud & Infra Services, Tech Support Engineer, Middleware Administration, Requirement

Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Notice Period: 3 Months

Analysis, Application Design, Middleware Development, Software Coding, Software Testing, TIBCO

EMS, Administrator, Hawk, JDBC, JMS, Perl Script, SQL, PL/SQL, Shell Script

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Having around 4.5 Years of I.T. Experience of experience in developing Mddleware solutions & Technical support. Have experience in different phases of the software lifecycle for integration projects ranging from Requirement Analysis, Design and Development. Worked as a Middleware Support engineer for TIBCO middleware. Expertise in TIBCO EMS.

Work Experience

Larsen & Toubro Infotech as Engineer- Cloud & Infra Services

Mar 2019 to Till Date

Clients CITI BANK

Environment TIBCO EMS and UNIX

Role TIBCO EMS

Project Domain Banking & Financial Services

TIBCO EMS and UNIX Skill/Tools Duration March 2019 - Till date

Project was involving with CITI for NAM Production support. We are Supporting Mddleware Applications for ICG Shared Services. Our application is used for integration with Front-end and back-end system through messaging services. NAM ProdOps project which involves supporting many integration components hosted on UNIX platforms We were responsible for Citi Production Support

My Roles and responsibilities:

As a team member, I was responsible for NAM ProdOps team supporting the Admin deployments Using TIBCO Administrator involving,

Regular Manual Health checks on various environment servers where the Production applications are deployed and status reporting on UNIX server slices

Monitoring Email Inbox for automated alarms and emails from other support teams like Application Team, DB, on UNIX and Window Admin servers

Service management monitoring for Incidents and Change Requests.

Responding to telephone calls from applications support and third line support on all INCs raised on Service Management Suite.

Ability to review 'old' logs to see what is 'normal' and what abnormal state/behavior.

Supporting the Application which involves maintenance of Application Services

Auctioning on the Incidents raised by the APP team on various alerts raised due to disruption of ProdOps Services., ensuring that the services and Applications are back without any outage.

Monitoring the various EMS, JMS queues and purging the queues on confirmation from Application Team.

Regular monitoring and cleaning of the disk spaces on UNIX server slices where the application is deployed. End to End testing in all the production environments by checking the end to end flow involving Application Teams,

identifying and fixing the components in case of failures in the flow.



Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Part of Regular Major releases every Quarterly and COB drills across all Production Line of Business.

Created Queues, Topics required for this application in TIBCO EMS.

Upgraded TIBCO environment from EWS 6.x to 8.x, automated creating ems objects queues, topics, bridges etc.

Did 24/7 on call support and coordinating with different teams for resolving the infrastructure issues

Involved in All cert Renewal Upgrades across all Production Line of Business.

Additional Responsibilities:

As a Team Member, I was also responsible for,

Preparing Shift-roster for team members to support 24*7 model and managing resources for each shift

Setting up team meetings, explaining current requirements to the team members, guiding them if they need any support.

Fetching the monthly/weekly incidents/Change tickets from Service-Now tool for analyzing the data, preparing reports to present in client meetings on monthly basis.

Accessing the impact of Issues, Create Impact Analysis document, provide fixes for the Defects raised on the team Queue.

Handling internal reports for; Training status, Knowledge Transfers.

Schedule and conduct meeting with clients to bridge requirement gap.

Co-coordinating with onsite.

CAPEGEMINI INDIA PVT LTD as Associate Consultant

Aug 2016 to Mar 2019

Clients Eneco Environment NA

Role Technical support Engineer

Project Domain Banking & Financial Services

Duration Aug 2016 - March 2019

My Roles and responsibilities:

As a team member, I was responsible for server and network monitoring and infrastructure management which includes knowledge of Windows and Linux

Monitoring and escalating hawk alerts to the concerned team

Coordinating between teams for production issues

Implemented an issue escalation process to identify critical issues and perform automated notifications and appropriate escalations.

Raising vendor tickets for any issues which need to be get support from vendor.

Co-coordinating with vendor, resolving issues by setting up meetings.

Responding to telephone calls from applications support and third line support on all INCs raised on Service Management Suite.

Supporting the Application which involves maintenance of Application Services.

Maintained and updated customer service database

Special Project implementation of new software, Patching servers, troubleshooting, Light project planning coordinated migration of servers to new data centers.

To provide effective communication for all types of incident logged in Service now.

Additional Responsibilities:

As a Quality Team Player, I was responsible for

Co-coordinating with onsite counterparts for update on Fixes

Maintaining Internal Reports for Incident Trackers

Co-coordinator for Client-Side trainings for both Onshore and Offshore

Train new employee and explain protocols and efficiently.

Tech Mahindra Ltd. as Trainee

Mar 2016 to Aug 2016

Clients NA Environment NA Role NA

Project Domain IMS

Duration March 2016 - August 2016

My Roles and responsibilities:

Fundamental IT IMS domain Practice (H/W, OS, Database, Storage, Cloud, Security, Application, Network and Services)

End User IT Management Practice (Window System and Linux System)

Network Management Practice (Cisco Switching and Routing, Security Management)

Soft skill Practice (Communication and Behavioral Development)

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from KIIT University, Bhubaneswar in 2016

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
TIBCO EMS, Administrator, Hawk	
JDBC, JMS, Perl script, SQL, PL/SQL	
TIBCO-EMS 6.x/8.x,	
TCP/IP, SOAP, HTTP, FTP, UDP	
01 11 0 1 1	

Snell Script	
BMS, HPSM, NAV-2009	
Nagios, SAP Logon tool, SCOM	
Service now	
SSH Secure Shell, Putty	
TIBCO HAWK, ITRS	
Windows 2000/2003/2008/2010	
Redhat Linux, Unix	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.